Fried, John H. E.; Papers ger014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
John H. E. Fried Papers
1911-1990
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger014
40 cubic ft.
The John H. E. Fried Papers consist of his professional correspondence, copies of his published and unpublished writings (manuscripts, typescripts, reprints and books), texts of numerous speeches and lectures (published and unpublished), personal documents, teaching materials, as well as Fried's research collections on topics relating to global human rights problems and remedies.
Biographical Sketch
John H. E. Fried (1905-1990), lawyer, professor and human rights activist, came to the United States in 1938 from Vienna, Austria shortly after its annexation by Hitler. Before immigrating to the United States, Fried, who received his Doctor of Law and Political Science from the University of Vienna in 1930, was a member of the Vienna Bar and also served a five-year term as panel member of the Vienna Labor Relations Court.
Upon his arrival in New York in the summer of 1938, Fried joined the Institute for Social Research at Columbia University. During the next few years, he wrote three highly acclaimed books. These include The Guilt of the German Army, 1942; The Significance of Democracy: Constitutional Developments and Labor Relations in Austria, 1944; and The Exploitation of Foreign Labor by Germany, 1945. He obtained a Ph.D. in Public Law and Government from Columbia University, held posts as research associate at Columbia University and the New School for Social Research, taught at City College and the Extension Department of Columbia, and became a senior official of the international secretariat of the International Labor Organization (I.L.O.), located in Montreal, Canada.
In January of 1947, the U.S. War Department requested Fried's services for a three-month survey of certain aspects of the law of war, and to serve as consultant to the U.S. Secretary of War, assigned to the U.S. War Crimes Tribunals in Nuremberg, Germany. In March 1947, Fried was asked to remain in Nuremberg as special legal consultant to the U.S. judges at the trials. He stayed to advise on questions relating to all aspects of the law of war and war crimes, crimes against humanity and crimes against peace, and many other international law questions. After the trials ended in spring 1949, Fried, by a decision of all presiding judges, was made their representative for the preparation of the official U.S. government publication of these trials. He was transferred to the Judge Advocate General's Office, Department of the Army, The Pentagon, where he worked until the end of 1950. The proceedings of the 12 trials were published in 14 volumes. Trials of War Criminals before the Nuremberg Military Tribunals (Washington: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1950-1953), with the introduction to each of the 12 cases stating: "John H. E. Fried, Special Legal Consultant to the Tribunals, reviewed and approved the selection and arrangement of the material as the designated representative of the Nuremberg Military Tribunals."
Over the next three decades, Fried held academic positions at the City College of New York, Columbia University, Pittsburgh University, the New School for Social Research (N.Y.), and from 1968 until his retirement as professor of Political Science at the Lehman College, Graduate Faculty of the City University of New York. He continued to serve the international community, working for the United Nations in various capacities. He worked as legal officer and program officer of the Technical Assistance Administration of the U.N., as legal advisor (on international law) to the Government of Nepal, and lastly as U.N. Non-Governmental Organization Representative of the Foundation for the Establishment of an International Criminal Court.
In addition to his book publications, Fried presented numerous lectures and papers at universities, national and international conferences. Seven articles were selected from the John H.E. Fried Papers and published in 1994 as Toward a Right to Peace. Selected Papers of John H. E. Fried. With a foreword by Roger S. Clark (Northampton, MA: Aletheia Press, c. 1994). Other collections of materials about John H. E. Fried are located at the Leo Baeck Institute (N.Y.) and the Simon Wiesenthal Center of the Yeshiva University of Los Angeles.
He died on 18 December 1990.
1905 Born 12 November, Vienna, Austria
1924-1929 Educated at Univ.of Vienna, Dept.of Law and Political Science
1930 Dr. of Law and Political Science, Vienna Univ.
1938 summer arrival in the U.S.
1938-1940 Research Associate, Inst. of Social Research, Columbia Univ.
1940-1942 Research Associate, New School for Social Research, N.Y.C.
1942-1943 Instructor, Dept. of Political Science, City College
1944 January becomes U.S. citizen
1944-1946 Senior member of the Secretariat, International Labor Office, Montreal
1946-1949 Special Legal Consultant to the Judges, U.S. War Crimes Tribunals, Nuremburg, U.S. Zone of Germany
1949-1950 (part-time) Expert, Div.of Human Rts., U.N., N.Y.C. and Expert, Judge Advocate General's Office, U.S. Dept. of the Army, Washington, D.C.
1949-1950 Instructor, Dept.of Political Science, City College, CUNY
1951-1954 Legal Officer and Program Officer, Technical Assistance Administration, U.N., N.Y.C.
1955-1963 (part-time) Member of the Faculty, New School for Social Research, N.Y.C.
1954-1963 (part-time) Adjunct Professor of Political Science, N.Y.Univ.
1963-1968 (interrupted by assignment to Nepal-see below) Adjunct Professor of Political Science, City College, CUNY
1964-1966 United Nations Expert on International Law, assigned to the Government of Nepal, Kathmandu, Nepal
1966-1970 Legal Consultant to the Somalia delegation at the U.N.
1968-1976 Professor of Political Science, Lehman College, and Graduate Faculty, City University of New York.
18 December 1990 Died
Scope and Contents
The John H. E. Fried Papers consist of 40 cubic feet of materials. The collection includes his professional correspondence, copies of his published and unpublished writings (manuscripts, typescripts, reprints and books), texts of numerous speeches and lectures (published and unpublished), personal documents, teaching materials, as well as Fried's research collections on topics relating to global human rights problems and remedies. His work in this area spanned more than four decades, from his service as Consultant to the Nuremberg judges through his later membership on the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy, and includes his time at the International Labour Organization in Montreal, Canada, as well as his affiliations with the United Nations, working as a legal consultant to the governments of Somalia and Nepal. Fried's correspondence includes: professional correspondence concerning publications, lectures, and professional organizations; correspondence with other legal scholars, including Leo Gross, Harold D. Lasswell, Hans Kelsen, Quincy Wright; correspondence with statesmen (Wallace McClure, State Dept.), political figures (Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford, Henry Kissinger), and notable individuals, including physicist Viktor Weisskopf, writer Erich von Kahler, social scientists Arvid Brodersen and Erich Fromm, scholar Léon Poliakov, and former Nuremberg judges, including the last surviving trial judge, Judge WilliamWilkins.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Subseries 1: Publications by John H. E. Fried, 1929-1990
Subseries 2: Speeches, 1931-1989
Subseries 3: Conferences, 1944-1990
Subseries 4: Time Magazine/Fortune, 1943-1944
Subseries 5: International Labour Office, Montreal, Canada, 1942-1954
Subseries 6: Yivo Institute Regesta Diplomatica Research Project, 1955-1963
Subseries 7: Brookings Institution Study, 1959-1963
Subseries 8: Nuremberg book project, ca. 1967-1975
Subseries 9: Manuscripts, 1929-1986
Subseries 10: Notes on various topics
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the materials in the collection were donated by John H. E. Fried in February 1988. Additional materials were added to the collection after Fried's death in 1990 by his widow, Nancy Buckley Fried.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Public Servants; Political Science; Military and Armed Conflict; Labor; Nuremberg War Crime Trials, Nuremberg, Germany, 1946-1949.; Political scientists--Austria; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Study and teaching.; Comparative government--Study and teaching.; Lecture notes; Manuscripts; Correspondence; Fried, John H. E.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.); City University of New York
- Biographical materials and documents, 1911-1990; 1; 51 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of early school and career documents from Vienna, records and correspondence documenting Fried's arrival and early years in the U.S., employment searches, as well as records of his appointments to positions with the U.S. Army and the United Nations. Also included in this series are texts of radio interviews given by Fried, 1949-1975.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Documents, 1911-1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 1)
  - Student records, documents, 1917-1928 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 2)
  - Student notebooks, Vienna University, 1927-1929 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 3)
  - Permissions to practice law, Vienna, 1930-1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 4)
  - Emigration documents, 1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: emigration, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 6)
  - Early contacts in the U.S., 1938-1939 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 7)
  - Recommendations, 1938-1939 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 8)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1938-1963 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 9)
  - Rosenthal, Karl August. Emigration efforts by Fried, 1938-1940 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 10)
  - Türkel, Helene. Emigration efforts by Fried, 1939-1941 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 11)
  - Türkel, Helene. Correspondence with Fried, 1938-1941 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 12)
  - Columbia University, student years, 1939-1941 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 13)
  - Columbia University, Ph.D. degree, 1942 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 14)
  - Naturalization, 1942 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 15)
  - Employment inquiries, 1943 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 16)
  - Applications for teaching positions (A - K), 1940s-1950s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 17)
  - Applications for teaching positions (L - Z), 1940s-1950s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 18)
  - Selective Service documents, 1940-1944 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 19)
  - Ration cards, 1944 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 20)
  - Department of the Army, employment records, 1946-1951 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 21)
  - Employment inquiries, records, U.N., 1946-1957 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 22)
  - Consultant to the U.N. on Human Rights (1949-1951). Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 23)
    Including Egon Schwelb, John P. Humphrey, George Brand.
  - "Tentative Outline for a Projected Study on The Protection of Basic Human Rights Through International Judicial Procedure (The Nurenberg Trials)", 1949 May 07 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 24)
  - Personnel forms, 1951-1959 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 25)
  - Leases on property, 1951-1978 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 26)
  - Department of State, Employment applications, records, 1951-1956 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 27)
  - U.N. Loyalty check, correspondence, documents, 1953 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 28)
  - Department of Defense, personnel records, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 29)
  - United Nations Technical Assistance Board, personnel records, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 30)
    See also Series 3 - Nepal.
  - Records of burglary, 1968 September 02 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 31)
  - Affidavit by John Fried, 1969 September (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 32)
  - Marriage certificate, John Fried's second marriage to Nancy Margaret Buckley, 1984 May 22 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 33)
  - Addresses, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 34)
  - Curriculum vitae, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 35)
  - Memberships, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 36)
  - Scrapbook clippings, The Guilt of the German Army, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 38)
  - Clippings about Fried, 1940s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 39)
  - Clippings about Fried, 1950s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 40)
  - Clippings about Fried, 1960s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 41)
  - Clippings about Fried, 1970s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 42)
  - Clippings about Fried, 1980s (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 43)
  - Radio interviews, 1949-1953 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 44)
  - Radio interview on P.O.W.s, WBAI, 1972 August (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 45)
  - Trial at Nuremberg, National Project Center for Film and the Humanities, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 46)
  - Alan Douglas Show, NBC, 1973 May 10 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 47)
  - Hanoi Radio interview, 1974 January (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 48)
  - Interview on Hanoi trip, WBAI, 1974 February 07 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 49)
  - Radio talk on the Electronic Battlefield, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 50)
  - Interview on Vietnam, WBAI, 1975 January 27 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and ), Folder 51)
- Correspondence and typescripts related to the UNESCO book project (published 1955, under the title: The Third Reich), ca. 1949-1952; 2; 2 cubic ft. 88 file folders
  John H. E. Fried served as Legal Officer and Program Officer of the United Nations Technical Assistance Administration, headquartered in New York City, from 1951-1954. The series contains some correspondence, primarily concerning personnel matters, as well as memoranda and agreements dated 1948-1954.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - The Third Reich. Reviews, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 1)
  - General correspondence, 1949-1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 2)
  - Almond, Gabriel, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 3)
  - Angell, Robert C., 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 4)
  - Arndt, Hinz, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 5)
  - Bauer, Riccardo, 1950-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 6)
  - Bauer, Riccardo. "Birth of Fascism in Italy", 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 7)
  - Bauer, Riccardo. "Strumenti e Metodi del Fascismo" / "Instruments et methods du fascism", 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 8)
  - Baumont, Maurice, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 9)
  - Betz, Werner, 1950-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 10)
  - Betz, Werner, "Die Sprache des Nationalsozialismus", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 11)
  - Brodersen, Arvid, 1948-1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 12)
  - Calamandrei, Piero, 1949-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 13)
  - de Franz, Marie Anne, 1949-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 14)
  - de Jong, Louis, 1950-1957; 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 15)
  - D'Entreves, A.P., 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 16)
  - d'Harcourt, Robert, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 17)
  - Dicks, Henry V., 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 18)
  - d'Ormesson, Jean, 1951-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 19)
  - Einaudi, Mario, 1950-1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 20)
  - Fawtier, Robert, 1949-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 21)
  - Fink, Troels, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 22)
  - Forell, Birger, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 23)
  - Forell, Birger. "The Attitude of Nationalsocialism to the Protestant Churches in Germany" / "Die Stellungnahme des Nationalsozialismus zu den evangelischen Kirchen in Deutschland", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 24)
  - Franck, Louis R., 1950-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 25)
  - Franck, L. "Diagnostic Economique et Social du Fascisme et du national-Socialisme", title page only, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 26)
  - Frederick A. Praeger, Inc., 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 27)
  - Fuerth, F. M., 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 28)
  - Godchot, J. E., 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 29)
  - Grasso, Frank, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 30)
  - Grégoire, F., 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 31)
  - Grumbach, Salomon, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 32)
  - Hammerich, Louis L., 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 33)
  - Heindl, Richard, 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 34)
  - Higgins, Benjamin, 1950-1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 35)
  - Johansson, Harry, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 36)
  - Jucker, Selina, 1950-1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 37)
  - Klineberg, Otto, 1949-1954; 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 38)
  - Kramer, Gerhard F., 1950-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 39)
  - Kramer, Gerhard F. "De l'influence du national-socialisme sur les systèmes judiciaire et policier", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 40)
  - Kramer, Gerhard F. "Die Lenkung des Organismus der Gesetzesanwendung" / "The Manipulation of the Legal Apparatus", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 41)
  - Lange, Oskar, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 42)
  - LaPiana, George, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 43)
  - LaPiana, George. "Fascism and the Vatican. Methods of Action and Propaganda", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 44)
  - Lasswell, Harold D., 1945-1954; 1957-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 45)
  - Latte, Kurt, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 46)
  - Lefebvre, Henri, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 47)
  - Lefebvre, Henri. "L'esthétique du fascism", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 48)
  - Lukacs, George, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 49)
  - Marinesco, Marica, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 50)
  - Mehta, Mohan Sinha, 1950-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 51)
  - Menon, P. N., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 52)
  - Milano, Paolo, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 53)
  - Money-Kyrle, R. E., 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 54)
  - Myrdal, Alva, 1950-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 55)
  - Pachter, Henry M., 1950-1952; 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 56)
  - Pachter, Henry. "Characteristic Devices of Nazi and Fascist Propaganda for the Conquest of Power", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 57)
  - Polanyi, Karl, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 58)
  - Poliakoff (Poliakov), Léon, 1949-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 59)
  - Poliakoff, L. "L'Instrument de l'Antisémitisme", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 60)
  - Prenant, Prof, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 61)
  - Quintanilla, Louis (Ambassador), 1950-1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 62)
  - Rueff, Jacques, 1949-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 63)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1938-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 64)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano. "Fascist Propaganda", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 65)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano. Publications, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 66)
  - Schokking, J. J., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 67)
  - Schokking, J. J. "Nazism's Way to Success", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 68)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur, 1950-1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 69)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur. "Nazification of the Middle Class", Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 70)
  - Scott, Frank, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 71)
  - Scott, John MacCallum, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 72)
  - Segerstedt, Torgny, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 73)
  - Seidenberger, George, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 74)
  - Sen, S. N., 1951-1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 75)
  - Smith, D. Mack, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 76)
  - Sturzo, Luigi, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 77)
  - Sturzo, Luigi. Publications, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 78)
  - Taylor, Telford, 1950-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 79)
  - Taylor, Telford. Publications, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 80)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 81)
  - Vermeil, Edmond, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 82)
  - Vernant, Jacques, 1948-1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 83)
  - Wallon, Henri, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 84)
  - Weidenfeld & Nicolson, 1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 85)
  - Wells, Hermann, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 86)